So yesterday was a nice day for all of us, and I said something
對你們，昨天是美好的，我說了些
of a different level.
不同層次的說話
We've been talking all the time
我們常常談論
about the mundane things
世俗的事情
and these things sometimes are very ...
這些事情有時 …
are of so much importance, we think.
我們以為很重要
But when I talked to you yesterday,
我昨天向你們講的話
I hope you all realized
是希望你們都意識到
that we have to now jump into
現在我們要跳進
another realm of a subtler understanding of Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽精微理解的另一個領域
First we are worried about
我們先擔心
our families, our children,
我們的家庭，我們的孩子
our households;
我們的家居
then, our marriages.
跟著是我們的婚姻
One after another all these questions came up,
這些問題一個接一個的出現
and we were concerned about all these things;
我們都很關注
little, little things.
這些小事
Then we also got concerned about the ashrams
我們也對我們管理的
which we were running:
集體靜室很關注
the problems of the ashram,
集體靜室的問題
what we have been doing,
我們在做些甚麽
how we have been facing the problems,
我們怎樣面對這些問題
how people are creating problems.
人們怎樣製造問題
That's how our humanity started
我們就是這樣謙虛地
acquiring a subtler understanding.
漸漸取得精微的理解
And then we also realized that
跟著我們會意識到
we are blessed by God,
神祝福我們
that there's something great
有某些偉大的
that is always looking after us,
更高的力量
some higher Force,
常常在照顧我們
some special Attention is there about us.
對我們特別關注
This is what we realized.
這都是我們意識到的
Today I was explaining how it happens,
今天我要解釋這是甚麽一回事
that how we realize
我們怎樣知道
that God is helping us too.
神在幫助我們
Any problem is an effect of some sort of a cause
一切問題都事出有因
- every problem.
每一個問題都是
Like Mona wrote a letter that she was driving
就如夢娜寫了一封信說，她驅車
in a motorway
在高速公路上
and the car went out of control,
汽車失控
and the brake would not act.
煞車掣失靈
And there was a car coming from the right,
有車從右面
car coming from the left,
從左面而來
cars going through in front and behind.
也有汽車在前面和後面穿插
And she felt that they'll be finished
她以為她們會完蛋
- two of them were traveling, two Sahaja yoginis.
她與另一位女霎哈嘉瑜伽士一起
So the cause was the car or the brake or whatever it was,
「因」是汽車，或煞車掣
the mechanism, and the effect was all the problem.
又或其他機械原因，「果」就是全部這些問題
So now, how to overcome that problem?
現在，該怎樣克服這些問題？
Supposing you try to neutralize the effect, you cannot,
你想中和後果，你卻不能
because cause is still there.
因為「因」仍然存在
You try to improve the cause, it doesn't work out.
你想改善「因」，但辦不到
Then what to do?
那麽，該怎麽辦？
So the easiest thing is to cross the cause,
最容易的是跨越「因」
to ascend over, to go beyond the cause;
昇過它，超越它
so the cause does not exist for you,
對你，「因」不再存在
so the effect does not exist for you.
「果」亦不再存在
As long as the cause exists in your attention,
只要你仍放注意力在「因」
the effect will be there.
「果」仍會存在。
So what did she do?
她該怎樣做？
She just prayed to Me, just thought of Me that
她只向我禱告，只想起我︰
"Mother, now it's my last chance" - that's all.
「母親，這是我的最後機會。」這樣就可以了
So the cause disappeared, because you go beyond it.
「因」消失了，因為你超越了它
And the effect also disappeared, and she was surprised.
「果」也消失了，她感到很驚訝
So you must ascend away from the cause.
所以你必須昇進遠離「因」
Now a problem: "my wife is like this",
現在的問題是︰「我的妻子是這樣的。」
"my husband like this," "my family life is this,"
「我的丈夫是這樣的。」「我的家庭生活是這樣的。」
"Sahaja yogis are like this" - all kinds of things are there.
「霎哈嘉瑜伽士是這樣的。」----各式各樣的事物都有
It's an effect. Now what's the cause?
這是「果」，「因」是甚麽？
- is such and such person.
是這樣那樣的人
All right, now what are we to get - relation of the cause.
好吧，我們怎可與「因」連上
Surrender it.
把它交託吧
You are, you have the right to do that.
你有權這樣做，有本領這樣做
You have a knack to do it, you can do it.
你可以做到，
You are capable of it, you are entitled to do it
你有能力,有資格這樣做，
- but you don't do it, you forget.
但你卻沒有這樣做,忘記了，
You just forget.
你只是忘記了
If you surrender that cause,
若你把「因」交託
the effects will go away.
「果」也會消失
But that is the thing at that time to remember,
現在你必須緊記
that you have to ascend.
你要昇進
To go beyond the cause is the best way to get rid of it.
超越「因」是最佳擺脫它的途徑
So I've been playing with you.
我曾經開你的玩笑
You had causes to say,
你有原因說
"Oh Mother, this is the problem. I have no job."
「啊！母親，這是問題，我沒有工作。」
Now I have a job, then the job is to be hard.
現在我有工作，但工作很辛苦
Then the wife is not there, so must have a wife.
又沒有妻子，我必須有妻子
The wife has a problem, so she is to be divorced
妻子有問題，必須與她離婚
- and that and that, and this is that.
這樣那樣，就是這樣
Then, "I am like that.
跟著︰「我就像這樣
I am very bad because there's a bhoot in me."
我很差，因為有亡靈附著我。」
So the bhoot is the cause.
亡靈就是「因」
"And I am behaving like this because there's a bhoot in me."
我有這樣的言行是因為我被亡靈附體。」
That's also a scapegoat, I think.
我認為這些理由都是代罪羊
So first you go beyond that, saying,
你必須先超越它，說︰
"What is bhoot? Who is bhoot?
「甚麽是亡靈？誰是亡靈？
I know my Mother.
我知道我的母親
And Mother, You look after this bhoot of mine" - that's all.
母親會照顧我的亡靈。」就是這樣。
But for that an emergency has to come to you,
緊急情況因此出現
otherwise you just don't do it, with that power.
沒有這種推動力，你是不會去做的
When you are in emergent condition,
當你處於緊急狀況
then it works out faster.
它成就得更快
When it is not emergency then it's half-hearted,
若不是在緊急情況，你不會全心全意去做
like Mona's condition.
就像夢娜的情況
There was another case where a
在另一事件
journalist was traveling from ...
有一位記者從……
or something and his brakes broke down,
他的車的煞車掣壞了
and he was with another journalist,
他與另一位記者一起
so both of them were coming - this another journalist told me.
他們兩個人來。另一位記者告訴我
The another one was Sahaja yogi.
他是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
So he found his brakes are not working
他發現煞車掣失靈
and he found his car is going,
車仍然在移動
in front there is a big truck coming up
迎面有一輛大貨車
and another truck coming from behind.
另一輛貨車則從後而來
And there was no way for him to turn or to get out of it,
沒有任何空位可以讓他轉車或讓他離開
and his brakes were horrid.
他的煞車掣真的糟透了
That was a emergency, you see.
這種緊急情況，你明白吧
Such an emergency that developed into his mind,
在這緊急情況，他的腦海中浮現
that "Oh God, now the last moment has come.
「天啊！最後時刻到了
Now we're finished."
我們會完蛋
There is a truck coming from there and another truck,
一部貨車從這裏來，另一部從那裏來
and within a split of a second he was to be finished.
一瞬間他就會完蛋
And he just told his friend, "Think of Mother" - that's all.
他卻只對他的朋友說︰「想著母親。」只是這樣
And what he found, that he was nicely crawling on the road
跟著他發現他的車在路上慢慢爬行
and the trucks were left behind, and the brake was working.
那些貨車已在他的身後，煞車掣妥當的運作
But that emergency has to come.
這種緊急情況必須出現
Human beings are such that unless and until
人類就是這樣，若不把
they are put into tight corners, they never do that.
他們迫入死角，他們永遠不會這樣做
Once they are in a tight corner, then they do it.
只有當他們被迫入死角，他們才會去做
That is the reason why people try to take ascetic life,
這是人為甚麽要過苦行的生活
because if you are an ascetic then you are in a tight corner.
因為若你是苦行者，你便是在死角裏
They go to Gobi Desert to create that emergency within you,
他們走到戈壁沙漠，令自己處於這種緊急的狀況
so that you think of God.
你因此想起神
But that's too late to go to the Gobi Desert.
但是太遲走到戈壁沙漠
They create problems for them to get into tight corners,
他們為自己製造麻煩，令自己走入死角
so that they can get out of it.
他們因此可以擺脫它
But for Sahaja yogis if they are wise, they need not have.
對霎哈嘉瑜伽士，若他們有智慧，是不需要這樣做
But how do we achieve it otherwise, without any ... ?
在沒有甚麽…我們可以怎樣達到呢？
Only way is meditation.
靜坐是唯一途徑
Everybody must meditate, it's the point.
每一個人都必須靜坐，這是重點
If you do not meditate, you can continue for a while.
若不靜坐，你可以
You may be all right for a while
繼續這樣一會兒
for two, three months, maybe two years,
可能兩三個月，或兩年都沒有不妥
but then you drop out.
跟著你便退出了
Many people think, "Oh, what's the need to meditate?
很多人想︰「啊！有甚麽需要靜坐
You see, it's all right.
你看，沒有不妥
If we don't meditate, doesn't matter." It's not so.
我們不靜坐，也不要緊。」不是這樣
Because in meditation only you grow.
因為你只能在入靜中成長
In emergency you suddenly grow, no doubt.
在緊急情況下，你忽然成長，這是無庸置疑的
I mean, you jump like a jack-in-the- box.
我的意思是你像魔術盒那樣跳出來
You just come up with a spring.
像有彈簧般跳出來
But if you have to have continuous growth
若你想繼續成長
then you must meditate,
必須靜坐
allow the thoughts after thoughts coming,
容許思維一個接一個的來臨
and then allow them to subside,
跟著讓思維消退
because you rise into the state of thoughtless awareness.
因為你昇進至無思慮的入靜狀態
And in that thoughtless awareness you grow.
在無思慮的入靜狀態中，你才能成長
And you grow in your detachment
你成長至對
to the cause of all the effects.
因果抽離
If there is no cause, there is no effect.
沒有因，便沒有果
But this is the problem with us,
我們的問題是
is that we do not meditate, normally.
我們通常都不靜坐
Only when it comes to absolute last point,
只有在最後關頭
now you'll have to fall in the well - then we think of it.
你快要跌進井裏，才會想起靜坐
Maybe at that moment you are helped,
或許在這時刻你會獲得幫助
but you don't grow.
但你卻不會成長
Growth can only come if you meditate.
只能透過靜坐才能成長
That is one very important part,
對有靜坐的人
is complete help to people who meditate in the normal way.
這才是真正的幫助
In the normal life, how do we grow?
在日常生活中，我們怎能成長？
If we have no oxygen, we cannot grow.
沒有氧氣，我們便不能生長
We have to have sufficient oxygen,
必須要有充足的氧氣
we have to have sufficient food,
充足的食物
we have to have all these things.
我們必須有這些
But in spirituality you grow through meditation.
但靈性上，你只能透過靜坐成長
There's no way out.
沒有其他途徑
Those who think they can grow are bumptious,
以為自己可以成長的人是很自大
actually bumptious people,
真的是傲慢的人
because they can talk a lot about Sahaja Yoga.
他們可以談論很多有關霎哈嘉瑜伽的事
I have seen people who talk too much about Sahaja Yoga.
我曾經見過有人對霎哈嘉瑜伽說得太多
They can give big lectures, this, that,
他們可以大發妙論
but have no vibrations at all.
卻完全沒有生命能量
They can't do any work for Sahaja Yoga,
他們不能為霎哈嘉瑜伽工作
they are not collective,
他們不合群
they have no sense to be collective,
沒有合群的意識
all kinds of problems.
有著各種問題
But the growth is to be achieved through meditation.
成長只能透過靜坐
That is one part of it.
其一是
That is, we can say, is the worship, is the puja.
我們可以說，是敬拜，是崇拜
Then you don't have to give up anything,
你們不用放棄甚麽
you just become detached,
只要變得不執著
detached from the cause itself.
不執著於「因」
That's one part of it.
這是其一
Secondly, that this I would say will
其二，我可以說是
take you to the subtler side of your emotional bindings,
你情感枷鎖的精微的一面
because emotional binding has given you
因為情感的枷鎖
certain identification:
令你有某些認同
you are a Christian or a Hindu or a Muslim,
你是基督徒，你是印度教徒，你是穆斯林
or this and that, or a British or any kind of a race,
你是這樣那樣，又或你是英國人，或其他種族的人
or whatever you have to call it.
無論你怎樣稱呼它
All those things will drop out,
所有這些都會消退
because you get a detached personality.
因為你擁有不執著的人格
So these emotional bindings - "he is my brother,"
這種情感的枷鎖…他是我的兄弟
"she is my sister," "I am worried about my wife,"
她是我的姊妹，我擔心妻子
"I am worried about my child"
我擔心孩子
- all these emotional bindings which
一切令你有
make you a smaller personality will drop out,
狹隘品格的情感枷鎖，都要消退
and you'll have one emotional binding,
你只有一個情感的枷鎖
is that "I am growing in my compassion.
就是在慈悲中成長
Compassion is active, my compassion is effective.
慈悲是積極的，我的慈悲就是果
My compassion is alight.
慈悲是燃燒的
My compassion is this discretion.
我的慈悲是明辨能力
I am a yogi."
我是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
And secondly you read about Sahaja Yoga,
第二，你閱讀有關霎哈嘉瑜伽
you know about Sahaja Yoga,
你懂得霎哈嘉瑜伽
you know the technique of Sahaja yoga,
懂得霎哈嘉瑜伽的技巧
you raise your kundalini,
你提昇你的靈量
you clean your chakras,
清潔你的輪穴
try to understand about mantras.
嘗試了解口訣
You master your mantras,
你掌握口訣
you master your deities,
掌握神祗
you please them.
你取悅祂們
All these things when they are done properly,
當你恰當地做這些事
then your mental bindings will drop out.
你思維的枷鎖便會消退
Those who think they are great scientists,
以為自己是偉大的科學家的人
they will know that all this is no science;
他們會知道所有這些都不是科學
the science of God's technique is much more.
神的科學比這多得多
Those who think that they are over-read,
以為自己閱讀大量書籍
well-read people, when they read about Sahaja Yoga
讀很多書的人，當他們讀到霎哈嘉瑜伽
and work it out on themselves and see for themselves,
而又能在自己身上成就到，當他們看看自己
and on others,
再看看別人
they will know that whatever they have read is all stupid,
他們便知道無論他們讀過甚麽書，那些書都是很無聊
has no meaning, is empty.
沒有意義，空洞的
And that's how a kind of an emptiness will come in,
這就是某種空洞感怎樣出現
emptiness of ego,
空洞的自我
because they'll see that knowledge is so great.
因為他們看到知識是很偉大的
Like Newton said that "Knowledge is like an ocean,
像牛頓說︰「知識就像海洋
and I am like a little child
我只像小孩子
collecting some pebbles at its shore."
在岸邊收集小卵石
What an understanding!
就是這種理解！
So that emptiness comes in you,
你感到空虛
and then the real knowledge starts coming into you.
跟著真正的知識開始臨到你身上
The identification with real knowledge comes.
真正知識的認同到來
You talk;
你說話
when you talk, that talk has an effect - that's a mantra.
當你說話，你的話有影響力，這是口訣
You just don't jabber,
你不會信口雌黃
"Oh, I am in Sahaja Yoga.
「啊！我在霎哈嘉瑜伽
I have been in Sahaja Yoga for fifteen years"
我在霎哈嘉瑜伽已經十五年了。」
- good for nothing.
一無事處
You may be there
你或許在
for a hundred years but you may remain a donkey as donkey is,
霎哈嘉瑜伽上百年，但仍然是個笨人
absolutely.
不折不扣的笨蛋
But you may have been there only for one year,
你或許只在霎哈嘉瑜伽一年
and you may become from a donkey a human being,
卻能從笨蛋變成人類
and a yogi too.
一位瑜伽士
But that is what we have to first of all
我們先要修補自己
recondition ourselves,
情感上
by attaching ourselves emotionally to Mother.
我們要依靠母親
I mean, you have an advantage
我的意思是你比
over many other yogis of the world who came, poor things,
其他瑜伽士更有優勢，這些可憐的傢伙
they had nothing to look forward.
他們沒有甚麽展望
They knew of a Primordial Mother, they knew about this,
他們知道有太初之母，他們是知道的
but they had no Form.
但他們卻沒有祂的任何形相
You have a Form.
你卻有形相
You are very fortunate and lucky people; you have a Form.
你是非常幸運的人，你擁有母親的形相
It's easy to adore a Form than to adore something abstract
敬拜有形相的比敬拜任何抽象
in the air, do you see;
的東西容易，你明白嗎
absolute consciousness,
這完全是意念
how do you adore it when you can't see it?
若你看不到祂，怎去敬拜祂呢？
But that attachment doesn't mean in any way
這種依靠不是
that you have to give Me anything.
你要給我甚麽
What do you give Me?
你能給我甚麽？
Nothing, but detachment from the cause.
你不能，你只能對「因」的不執著
And this works out - you have seen it in your lifetime.
它可以成就到，你已經在你的人生中看到
You also say that "It works out, Mother,
你說︰「它能成事，母親，不知何故
somehow it worked out."
它能成事。」
What is bandhan?
甚麽是班丹？
It's nothing but you are attaching yourself to your Mother,
只是對母親的依靠
you're just telephoning to Her.
只是打電話給她
This is a telephone going to your Mother,
打電話給母親
that's all.
就只是這樣
You know I also play with you, I also say,
我也知道我常開你們玩笑，我也說
"All right, I am giving you a bandhan."
「好吧，我為你做班丹。」
I am giving bandhan to Myself!
我也為自己做班丹！
It's a telephone call,
這是來電
just a telephone call.
只是來電
But the faith has developed now that yes,
現在信心已經建立，是
this is the real faith,
是真正的信心
where you get completely detached in your emotional things.
你對有感情枷鎖的事物完全抽離
It's just "My mother" - all right, just give her a bandhan,
這只是「我的母親。」好吧，只要為她做班丹
finished. "My father" - give him a bandhan.
就可以了。「我的父親。」為他做班丹
"My brother" - give him a bandhan,
「我的兄弟。」為他做班丹
whatever it is.
無論甚麽事
Bandhan, whatever it is.
無論甚麽事，只要做班丹
You are putting that ... in the bonds of your Mother.
你把事情…與母親連上
But you are not conscious that you are doing that.
你卻並未意識到你在做著些甚麽
You are just binding them with the love of your Mother
你只是把事情與
which is flowing through your hands.
流通於你雙手的母親的愛連上
What are these vibrations, is your Mother's love.
這些生命能量是甚麽，是母親的愛
You've got it,
你已經得到
it is flowing through you.
它流通於你
But what about your love for your Mother?
但你對母親的愛
And that is what I find,
又怎麽樣？
that at the time when there is complete emergency
我發現在緊急關頭
that surrender comes in, and it works.
你自會交託，它可以成事
So there's no need to create any emergencies.
沒有需要製造緊急狀況
You must slow and steadily work it out,
你必須緩慢穩定的成就它
and it will build up by itself within you.
它會在你內裏建立
You will have that power within you, I assure you.
你內在自會有這力量，我可以向你保證
But meditation is one way;
一是透過靜坐
another is the knowledge of Sahaja Yoga.
一是透過霎哈嘉瑜的知識
Not showing off, not telling others,
不是炫耀，不是告訴別人
but working it out in yourself - different chakras,
而是自己去成就----不同的輪穴
how they work out,
他們怎樣可以成就到
on yourself, not on others.
在自己身上成就，不是在別人身上
Once you start teaching others, it's a bhoot in you.
當你開始教導別人，是有亡靈附在你身上
You'd better learn it for yourself, even within yourself.
還是為自己學習比較好
I know who has mastered which chakra, which ....
我知道誰掌握哪個輪穴，哪個…
Nobody tell others that
沒有人會告訴別人
"this is the way to do it," that's absolute nonsensical ego.
「是這樣做的。」這絕對是荒唐的自我
So such things should not be done.
這種事不要做
If somebody asks you, you can tell
若有人問你，你可以個別的告訴他
individually, but on a large scale you do not give lectures
但你不能大規模的演講，
on that, and don't confuse people.
不要混淆別人
Now, so we have two things,
現在我們要克服兩種枷鎖
that we have to get over our emotional
就是粗淺的情緒
grossness and our mental grossness;
和粗淺的思維
same with our physical grossness.
肉身上的粗淺也要克服
Physical grossness can be overcome
肉身的粗淺是可以克服的
if you surrender yourself,
若你把自己
to one medicine, is vibrations.
交託給一種良藥，這種良藥就是生命能量
Like Anupama, My grandchild, told her mother,
就像阿努帕瑪，我的孫兒，他告訴他的母親
"You are born in allopathy,
你在Allopathy出生
then you are following homeopathy.
你接受同類療法(Homeopathy)
Tomorrow you'll find out some jumbopathy,
明天你會找到Jumbopathy
then some numbopathy!
跟著是Numbopathy
So, but I am born in God
我在神之內出生
and I follow only God's pathy,
所以我只追隨神的療法(pathy)
and God will look after me
神會照顧我
and God will cure me."
醫治我
So My daughter said, "Why? You may also change."
我女兒說︰「為甚麽？你可以作出改變。」
She said, "Why?
他說︰「為甚麽？
Because God never changes."
因為神從不改變
Simple answer: God will cure you.
答案就是這樣簡單，神會醫治你
But you must have that much ascent to say that,
但你必須昇進至某個高度才能這樣說
as you just jump out at the time of emergency.
但你卻只在緊急狀況時
Same sort of an urge,
才跳昇
that same sort of a personality should be within you
要這樣說你必須處於相同的緊急狀況,，
to say that. Just if you say,
你內在有相同的人格。若你只說︰
"Oh God, please save me,"
「神啊！請拯救我。」
God has no time for such people.
神對這類人沒時間
You have no time for God, God has no time for you either
你沒時間給神，神也沒時間給你
- a simple thing.
就是這樣簡單
So from sublime to mundane things when we come,
從高尚到俗世的事物
we exist in both the things
我們存在於這兩者之間
and we are effective.
我們都是很有效率
Whether we are in the lamp or in the light or in the oil,
無論我們在燈下，在光下，在油燈下
we are at a subtler point;
我們都在精微這一點上
and we,
若是我們
if we give the effectiveness
引發「果」
without being the cause.
但「因」卻不是從我們而來
Because you are beyond the cause,
這是因為我們已超越了因
so there is no need to create any cause for anything,
不需要為任何事創造因
but you see the effect.
你卻看到果
So once the cause is finished effect is achieved,
當因結束，果亦已達到
and it's achieved what is to be achieved,
它成就要成就的
the correctness of it.
成就正確的一面
The correct thing you get.
你取得正確的事物
You do not get perverse thing,
不是墮落的事物
but if you go with a cause then you can have perversity,
若你仍帶著因，那麽你仍很倔強
you can have all kinds of problems.
仍可能出各種問題
So the best thing is to detach yourself from causes
所以最好還是從因中抽身
and then you get the effect,
那麽你便取得果
like as I told you that the brake got all right.
就如我告訴你，煞車掣會妥當
The effect was there,
但果仍在
the car was all right,
汽車沒有問題
everything was fine so the effect was all right;
各樣事情都妥當，所以果亦妥當
but the cause was lost.
但因卻消失了
There was no cause.
再沒有因
Why? How?
為甚麽？怎會這樣？
How the thing was perfected?
為甚麽事情會變得完滿
If you ask the effect of it, you say how did you get it?
若你問它的果，你說你是怎會有它呢？
You can't explain, it didn't work out.
你解釋不了，這也不能成就
So because the cause is missing
因為因消失了
you cannot put it to any cause;
找不到因
you sometimes say it's divine the way it's worked out.
有時你也可以說這是上天成就事情的方式
So the only cause that is really effective is divinity.
所以唯一真正有效的「因」是神性
But the divinity should not be just as
神性並非只是
a mundane sort of a thing,
俗世的事情
"All right, yes, Mother's photograph is there, namaste.
好吧，對，母親的相片就在這裏，向她問好
Good. Namaste. Good morning, Mother" - finished.
好吧，向她問好，早晨，母親。」就是這樣
That's not the way.
不是這樣
You have to know your Mother,
你必須認識你的母親
and you have to love your Mother
愛你的母親
- that is what it is.
就是這樣
It's very embarrassing to say that you must love Me.
說你要愛我是很尷尬的
But as a Mother in this lifetime
作為母親，在這一生中
I have had many embarrassing things,
有很多令我尷尬的事
and one of them is this,
其一是我不知
that I don't know how to tell the children.
怎樣告訴我的孩子這些
Now this is the fact.
這是事實
So you need not go through any emergencies
你們不需要經歷任何緊急狀況
or any such problems.
或任何這種問題
You just develop yourself in such a way
你只要以這種方式發展
that you are so developed that it just acts and works out.
你是已經發展，它自會起作用，自會成就到
So I'll give you a example of that.
讓我給你一個例子
It works the least in England,
它在英國成就得最少
surprisingly, where I've worked the most
這是很令人驚訝,雖然我為英國工作得最多
- least in England.
但英國卻成就得最少
I'll give you a simple example, now.
我給你一個簡單的例子
You see, your coming to India was decided
你決定來印度
I don't know how many months back.
我也不知道是多少個月之前決定
I have been to India once and I'm going second time,
我曾經到印度一次，我會再到印度
and England is the only place
英國是唯一你要
where you have to pay your money directly.
直接付款的地方
People have not yet paid,
他們仍未付錢
but Australians have done it.
澳洲人已經付了
Australians, who are eighty, eighty-five people have done it,
有八十…八十五個澳洲人已經付了
but English have not done - everything they are slow.
但英國還未，他們每樣事情都很慢
But when it comes to ego they are the first,
但說到自我，他們卻走在最前
their flags are the first.
他們的旗幟是最前的
In the ego, where is it generated? - in England the great.
自我在哪裏產生？在大英帝國
So when it comes to doing something they are the slowest,
說到要做一點事時，他們是最慢
when it comes to criticism they are the highest,
說到批評，他們居首位
and then when it comes to the ego suddenly you'll see,
說到自我，忽然你會看到他們
give them any position,
佔任何位置
it's ....
它是…為甚麽？
Why? Again you can explain, because there is a cause.
你再次可以解釋，因為「因」
You'll say it is inertia,
你會說因為惰性
blame someone, or it's a bhoot,
你會責備別人，或說是亡靈
or it's my ego or my superego, it's not myself.
又或是我的自我或超我，卻永遠也不會是自己
Myself, I am all right.
我很妥當，
Some cause.
是其他原因
Why you have not paid so far?
你為甚麽還未付錢？
It's such a problem;
這就是問題
I have to go now.
我現在要走了
If you were not coming you should not have come,
若你不來，就不要來
but if you are paying, you better pay for it.
若你要付錢，最好現在付
Now, what's the matter with you?
你發生了甚麽事？
They started with fifty people,
開始時他們有五十人
now they end up with thirty-five.
現在卻只有三十五人
We have arranged for it,
我們已經為它安排好
we have ordered for things and
物資已經訂購了
we have got the buses and all that;
巴士亦已安排好
now they are missing.
現在他們都消失了
Nobody asked you to come.
沒有人要你來
On the contrary I was saying,
相反，我說
"Keep it low. Keep it low, so that we'll make it nice."
低調點，低調點，那麽我們可以安排得更好
But you cannot have less than 350
但不能少過三百五十人
or you can have three hundred,
或可有三百人
you can have two hundred,
二百人也可以
but you cannot just have 210.
但不能只有二百一十人
Where to put them?
怎樣安置他們？
A simple thing - see all the mundane style.
這樣簡單的事情----便能看到俗世的處事方式
But in other places what they have done?
在其他地方，他們做了些甚麽？
"All right, we have to go. Mother will work it out."
「好吧，我們要走了，母親自會解決。」
It's worked out.
它解決了
Everybody has got money, everything done, it's all here.
每個人都拿到錢，每件事都辦妥，都在這裏
Americans have done it, surprisingly,
很令人驚訝，美國人做妥了
but English
但英國人
- they don't know whether they are going or not.
他們不知道自己來不來
Still there are some.
仍有些人不知道
Poor Gavin has to run up and down for all of you.
可憐的加文必須為他們跑上跑下
I tell you, he is the one who has such patience.
我告訴你，只有他有這份耐性
And I was amazed
我很驚訝
that there are still eleven people who have not paid,
仍有十一人未付錢
can you believe it?
你相信嗎？
I mean, it's such a simple thing.
我的意思是這樣簡單的事情
If you don't want to go, don't go.
若你不想來，就不要來
If you want to go, you go.
若你想來，便來吧
Tell him you are not going or you are going, finished.
告訴他你來或不來，就可以了
I mean, nobody wants you there.
我的意思是沒有人想你來
But even this little thing you cannot because
就算是這種小事你也辦不妥，因為
you have a kind of a ...
因為你有一種…
because, because this has happened,
因為，因為這已經發生
because that has happened, because ...
因為那樣事情發生...
So the English have to come up much more,
所以英國人要迎頭趕上
because I have really worked for you people very, very hard,
我真的為你們非常非常的努力工作
and again God has given Me work again five years more;
神再給我五年為你們工作，
I don't know what we are going to do.
我不知道我們該做些甚麽
Sometimes I feel I should not be back, because no use.
有時我感到我不應回來，因為是沒有用的
This is a small example I am giving,
這是我給你們的小小例子
very small example,
很小的例子
it's very mundane type.
這是很俗世
You can see in other places also, like that.
你也在別的地方看到像這樣的例子
You tell them anything,
當你告訴他們任何事
"But why, Mother, it happens like that?
為甚麽？母親，是這樣發生嗎
Why do I do like this?"
為甚麽我要這樣做
I mean, asking Me a question, asking Me the cause!
我的意思是他們問我，問我起因
"Why did I behave like this? Why do I get into temper?"
我為甚麽要有這樣的言行？我為甚麽會生氣？」
Like I have known people
就像我知道
who have been coming to Sahaja Yoga,
有些來霎哈嘉瑜伽
doing Sahaja Yoga and all that,
練習霎哈嘉瑜伽的人
but then they go to some other Steiner's place.
他們卻走到一些Steiner的地方
Then they go to some other courses.
參加其他課程
I mean, they have no faith in Me - Sahaja Yoga.
我的意思是他們對我沒信心，對霎哈嘉瑜伽沒信心
They are practicing this, they are practicing that like mad,
他們像瘋子一樣練習這些，練習那些
still going on.
這種情況仍然持續
That's only possible in England, I tell you,
只有英國是這樣，我告訴你
nowhere else - it's a speciality.
其他地方不是這樣，它很特別
I have known of so many people who came to Sahaja Yoga;
我知道很多來霎哈嘉瑜伽的人
without practicing Sahaja Yoga,
沒有練習霎哈嘉瑜伽
curing, helping them in Sahaja Yoga, working it out.
卻醫治人，在霎哈嘉瑜伽幫助人，把事情成就
They leave Sahaja Yoga.
當他們離開霎哈嘉瑜伽後
They're going to this place, that place, that ....
他們走到這個地方，那個地方…
Is this the way?
是要這樣嗎？
Now I have known lots of people who
我知道很多人
try to blame the leadership.
想指責領導
I am telling you all these things because
我告訴你這些是因為
I was very sick when I came here, really I tell you,
當我來到這裏，染了很重的病，我告訴你是真的
I was sick for eight days and I was sick even afterwards;
我病倒了八天，之後病仍未痊癒
because you know, you are all in My body and I suffer,
你們都知道，你們全都在我身體內，我因此受苦
so I must tell you.
所以我必須告訴你們
And then they say the leadership is no good,
他們說領導不好
leader should be very strong, the leader should be this,
領袖必須很強，領袖必須是這樣
and their leader must have a big thing in his hand,
他們的領袖必須手握武器
and they said if he hits us,
他們說若他襲擊我們
we are not going to be all right.
我們將不會妥當
Again the cause; again the cause.
這再次是「因」
I tell you, you have one of the best leaders in Gavin,
我告訴你，加文是其中一位最佳的領袖
and I must tell you,
我必須告訴你
he is the man who spent a lot of money.
他花了很多錢
Without telling Me he has covered many expenses,
他沒有告訴我他支付了很多費用
his office has worked for us.
他的辦公室為我們而設
He took all nonsensical people.
他接收所有荒唐的人
If I told him, "This fellow is getting some ego,"
若我告訴他︰「這傢伙有點自我
he'll employ in his office.
他便會雇用他
If I say, "This fellow has got bhoots,"
若我說︰「這傢伙有亡靈附體。」
He has worked with such bhoots
他與那些我甚至
that I could not manage them even for a day.
一天也應付不了的亡靈一起工作
He tries his level best to go to people and tell them that,
他盡力告訴他們︰
"See now, come."
「現在你看，來吧。」
He has saved so many people
憑他的感覺,憑他的理解
by his sense, by his understanding;
他救了很多人
but the only thing is he, openly he doesn't lead,
唯一的是他沒有公開的帶領
that's his mistake.
這是他的錯
He should openly tell,
他應該公開的說
"You are a bhoot and get cured, then you'll be all right."
你是亡靈，你會得到醫治，你會妥當
But if you say,
但若你說︰
"Come here. You see, you are a bhoot, doesn't matter.
來這裏，你要明白，你是亡靈，不要緊
I have got lemons, ..., chillies. You sit down."
我有檸檬…還有辣椒，你坐下
Then, "Mother,
跟著︰「母親
he is identifying himself with the greatest bhoot."
他已經視自己與最偉大的亡靈一起
Let us face it.
讓我們面對它
If you have understanding of your leader,
若你了解你的領袖
then you should know that I know better than you know
你應該知道我比你
about it.
更加了解他
And this is very saddening sometimes.
有時這是很令人傷感
Why don't you understand the sheer goodness of a person?
你們為甚麽不去了解這個人好的一面？
The amount of bhoots he has tolerated in his office,
在他辦公室裏，他要容忍的亡靈數目
I tell you, I can't stand them for more than one day,
我告訴你，連一天我也忍受不了
some of them.
他們有些
So egoistical, some of them, off their heads,
是很自我中心，有些失去了理性
and some of them are so bhootish
有些很嚴重
that even if they come downstairs
就算他們走下樓梯
I get a pain in the stomach, in My house.
我也會胃痛，在我的房子裏
But he stood them.
但他卻支持他們
Why? What was the need?
為甚麽？有甚麽需要這樣？
Just that he thought that he'd help them.
他只是想幫助他們
Whenever I told him that "This person is bhootish,"
當我告訴他︰「這個人受亡靈影響得很深。」
I find him employed by Mr Gavin Brown.
我發覺加文雇用了他
Then one day I had to tell him, "Sack all of them,"
有天我必須告訴他︰「把他們全都解雇吧！」
and they were sacked.
他們被解雇
Why do we have the maximum number of bhoots in England,
為甚麽英國有最多的亡靈
I can't understand.
我真的不明白
Is it necessary to have them around?
有需要他們在周遭嗎？
On the day when I am going I should not tell you these things,
在我要走的日子，我不應告訴你這樣的事情
but when I go away I find these bhoots come back,
當我走後，我發覺這些亡靈全都回來了
and they become the causes, and the effects are shown.
他們成為「因」，「果」也顯現
So I have to make a complete open picture to you
我必須給你完整的圖畫
to see that you can ascend to the highest of highest,
在這個國家的偉大土地上出生
being born on this great land of this country.
你可以昇進至最高
But you can also go very down, I have seen that.
但也可以降至很低，我曾經見過這樣
Because you're always blaming someone,
因為你常常指責別人
last of all Gavin,
最不應受指責的是加文
and this is the worst thing that you have done.
這是你做最差的事
Let anybody say that to Gregoire -
若把這件事告訴葛雷瓜
he'll chop that person off ten times
他會砍這人十次
and bring that person to me in chopped stages!
再把他帶來給我
Really, I mean!
真的
He'll say, "What nonsense!
他會說︰「真荒唐！
All right, it's ... go ahead."
好吧…照辦吧」
You tell Mr.Warren,
你告訴華倫先生
I don't know what he'll do with all of the Australian type.
我不知道他以澳洲的處事方式會做些甚麽
They are all gems, no doubt.
他們全是寶石，毫無疑問
But you deserve a man like Gavin.
你們值得擁有像加文這樣的人
I thought, they are special people
我想他們是特別的人
that I've worked for you so much,
我為你們努力工作
but I am amazed.
我很驚訝
The decent people don't need such leaders, do you?
正派的人不需要這種領袖，你要嗎？
But the people who are decent now
澳洲人被
turn out to be Australians, surprisingly,
證明是正派的人，很令人驚訝
the way they behave towards Me:
他們對待我的方式
so sweet they are, you'd be surprised,
是那麽可愛，你會很驚訝
the children you know.
加文。你也知道那些孩子
Gavin, he bought some cups and saucers for Me
他為我買了一些杯碟
because when I go there they thought they'll give Me tea
因為他們想在我來時
in good cups and saucers.
可以有好的杯碟為我準備茶點
So he bought for all the centers one cup and saucer,
所以他為每一個中心購買
good one.
一套好的杯碟
So the children, little, little children,
孩子，小孩子
they collected money;
他們負責收錢
after all, Mother will have a cake, also must have a plate.
無論如何，要給母親奉上糕餅，必須有碟子
So they sent a check here, just see - how sweet!
所以他們把支票寄來，你看看，他們是那麽可愛
But I never eat cakes, you know that, but still
我從不吃糕餅，你們是知道的，但仍然…
- so sweet the children, I should say.
我必須要說，孩子是那麽可愛
What is the reason?
甚麽原因
Why do we dominate or get dominated?
我們為甚麽要支配人或受人支配
Why?
為甚麽
Again the cause.
再次是因為「因」
Go beyond the cause.
超越「因」吧
I bless you again and again that when I come next time,
我一次又一次祝福你們，在我下次再來的時候
see that you don't make any mistakes anymore.
要看到你們不再犯錯
Meditate and meditate and meditate,
靜坐、靜坐、靜坐
and when you come to India some of you,
當你們來印度
I would like to show you as my prize things
我很樂意向你展示，你是我努力工作
from where I've worked, you know.
取得的獎品。你知道嗎
Even where I've not been, you see,
就算我不曾到過的地方
somebody else has given realization to someone in Nepal,
有人把自覺給了尼泊爾人
you see,
他們是
and they are wonderful flowers;
奇妙的花朵
and here am I, something wrong with Me!
我就在這裏，我有點出錯
Where I have worked,
我在哪裏工作
people are more worried about the causes.
哪裏的人對「因」便有更多的憂慮
I have to really make a very, very
我必須
straightforward appeal to you that now,
呼籲你們
grow within yourself.
請在內裏成長
Are you magnanimous,
你是否寛宏？
are you generous,
是否慷慨？
are you systematic?
是否有條理？
Are you impressive,
是否令人留下印象？
are you kind,
是否仁慈？
are you collective?
是否合群？
Are you attached to all these nonsensical things still?
是否仍依附著一些荒唐的事物？
Do you talk big,
是否說話浮誇？
do you give big lectures?
是否大發妙論？
Humble down yourself,
請謙卑下來
and then you'll see your greatness.
你便看到自己偉大之處
Unless and until you put your head down to your heart,
除非你真心的把頭垂下
how will you see your Mother?
你又怎能看到你的母親？
I wish you all great luck now,
我希望你們都交上好運
and happy Christmas to you and happy New Year,
祝你們聖誔快樂，新年進步
and a very great New Year in spiritual growth.
在靈性昇進上有豐盛的新一年
Let's show it.
讓我們顯示它
Let all of us decide today.
讓我們今天決定
Forget about your wives and husbands and children,
把你的妻子，丈夫，孩子
and this and that nonsense.
一切荒謬的事物忘記吧
Now you are yogis, you are united with Divine.
你現在是瑜伽士，你與上天連上
Grow in it, prosper in it.
請在它內成長、在它內昌盛
May God bless you all.
願神祝福你們
Now the today's program
今天的節目
should not be very big because we are not allowed
不應大規模
lot of time,
因為沒有太多時間
but it's nice that today we could have a little puja of farewell.
今天最好有一個告別的小崇拜
But it should be a very small ... because it is,
必須是小的崇拜…因為它是
how much you receive is the point,
最重要是你可以接受多少
because before going I don't want to have all kinds of chakras,
因為在我走前，我不想
you see, going into spasms.
每一個輪穴都抽搐
I am sometimes afraid of a puja in England.
我有時對在英國做崇拜感到有點怕
Gavin, I think you can just ...
加文，我想你只要...
It's the mastery.
這是掌握
You must have the mastery,
你必須先
upon yourself first of all.
掌握自己
If you are not a master you cannot act
若你不是導師，你不能行動
- and upon your instrument, that's the point.
對你的工具，這是重點
And I would not like anybody to disrespect
我不希望任何人
the leaders at all.
不尊重領袖
You may be very intelligent, that's outside Sahaja Yoga.
你可能非常聰明，但這是無關霎哈嘉瑜伽
In Sahaja Yoga you have to listen to your leaders
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，你必須聽你的領袖的話
and respect, and nobody should try to find faults.
尊重你的領袖，不要找他的錯處
I know his faults, what are his faults are,
我知道他的缺點，知道他有甚麽缺點
and I know how to deal with them.
我知道怎樣處理
Everybody should try to strengthen.
每一個人必須鞏固自己
Now I would say in Australia, which is a modern thing,
我可以說在澳洲，這是現代的事物
I should say that the whole thing works like one body.
我必須說整體像一個身體般運作
Nobody questions Warren.
沒有人質疑華倫
They telephone to him, they tell him, they collect money,
他們致電給他，他們告訴他，他們收錢
they put the money - it's all working like one body.
他們把錢…全都像一個身體般運作
Here everybody is trying to cut the head
但在這裏，每個人都想把頭砍下
- or attack the heart;
或攻擊心臟
that's your heart, that's your brain.
這是你的心臟，這是你的腦袋
So please remember all of you should offer services
請記著，在批評前，
to Gavin,
你們都必須為加文，
to Sahaja Yoga,
為霎哈嘉瑜伽
before criticizing.
提供服務
Those who say the books are not arriving,
說書籍還未到達的人
let them take over the books.
請他們接管那些書籍
Even booking My seats and all that he has to run, I know;
就算是預訂我的座位，還有其他也是他管理
whatever you may say about ... he used to do all this.
無論你說甚麽…通常這些工作都是他做的
So you should offer your services also,
所以你也要提供服務
to do these jobs.
做這些工作
Otherwise Sahaja Yoga won't work out.
否則霎哈嘉瑜伽就成就不了
We are not only here to take blessings
我們來這裏不單是要接受祝福
but we have certain duties also,
我們還要負一些責任
and that's what everybody should offer,
就是每一個人都必須要提供
their measure: what can I do, how can I help?
要估量︰我可以做甚麽，我可以怎樣幫忙？
What is the work? Let's see now.
有甚麽工作？讓我們現在看看
I hope in the next meeting you all should sit down
我希望在下次會面時，你們全都坐下來
and find out what you can do.
找出你可以做些甚麽
A group can be formed: two, three persons can sit and do it
可以組成一組，二個，三個人
with love, with attention,
以愛心，全神貫注的去做
so that his burden will be reduced, and you will all feel
那麽他的重擔便可以減輕，你們全都
the joy that you are doing something for Sahaja Yoga.
感覺到喜樂，因為你為霎哈嘉瑜伽做了點事
Mother has done so much for you,
母親為我們做了很多工作
what have you done for Sahaja Yoga?
我們為霎哈嘉瑜伽又做了些甚麽？
You want to have nice ashrams,
你想有好的集體靜室
nice place to live there,
好的地方居住
all right.
好吧
You want to have comfortable places, cheaper places,
你想有舒適的地方，便宜的地方
You want to have good health,
你想有健康
all right.
好吧
You want to have fine children, all right; enjoy your life.
你想有可愛的孩子，好吧，享受你的人生
But what about giving,
但付出又怎樣
giving your heart,
付出你的真心
your respect?
你的尊重
Next time when I come back,
下次我回來時
I want to see that you are all growing as one body.
我希望看到你們全都成長成一個個體
At least the Heart should be integrated,
若不能
if nothing else.
最少心臟能夠整合
Imagine a heart
試想像心臟
which has the valves which pulsates at various times,
的活門在不同的時間跳動
all muscles going at different wavelengths.
所有肌肉以不同波段移動
How can this universe survive with a heart like this?
像這樣的心臟，這個宇宙怎能生存？
So I have to request all the,
所以我請求你們
all the cells of the Heart to be alert,
所有心臟的細胞要警覺
to be one in unison with God,
要與神合一
and in loving care of the whole universe.
在整個宇宙的關愛下
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們
So what is this puja supposed to be today?
今天該有甚麽崇拜？
It's farewell puja
今天是告別崇拜
today, so let's have it,
就讓我們有一個這樣的崇拜
just before the birth of Christ.
在耶穌基督出生前
Let Christ be born within us.
讓基督在我內裏出生
Let's be, like Him,
讓我們像祂，
the one who always insisted,
祂常常堅持
"Love your brothers. Love your sisters."
愛你的兄弟，愛你的姊妹
Who are your brothers and sisters?
誰是我的兄弟姊妹？
He asked the question too,
祂也問這個問題︰
"Sahaja yogis are my brothers and sisters."
霎哈嘉瑜伽士是我的兄弟姊妹
Somebody offered at the altar.
有人在聖壇上說
He said, "What are you to offer at the altar?
你可以在聖壇上奉獻甚麽？
Have you reconciled with your brother?"
你有否與你的兄弟協調？
Have you reconciled?
有否協調
First reconcile, and then bring flowers to Mother.
先協調，才把花朵帶給母親
He said it already.
祂已經說了
Think of Him, how forgiving He was,
想想祂，祂是何等寛容
how magnanimous, how great, and how
何等寛大，何等偉大，祂怎樣
He thought of His Father all the time,
每時每刻都想著祂的父親
completely dedicated,
完全的奉獻
doing His work.
做祂的工作
So with all praises to Christ
讚美基督
and to His Mother who worked
讚美以
in a very potential manner,
潛在方式工作的母親
we have to today within ourselves
我們今天在內裏
awaken that great Spirit,
喚醒偉大的靈
which is actually the Aumkara.
它實際上是Aumkara
Even the memory,
就算是記起它
even the idea of that
想起它也
is so joy-giving.
令人喜樂
Let His life be reflected in your lives.
讓祂的生命反映你的生命
You have to be true Christians.
你要成為真正的基督徒
Let's have ... what is it? ....
讓我們有…這是甚麽？
I think ... Now I would say, next time when you come to puja,
我想…我可以說，下次你來到崇拜
all of you must have
你們必須唸誦
the hundred-and-eight names of the Goddess.
女神的108個名號
You must have all the papers that are there.
你們必須有這些紙張
Like we have these books,
就像我們有這些書籍
all of us must have these papers,
我們必須有這些紙張
not only one person should have.
不單一個人有
We should try to remember certain things also:
我們也要記著一些事情
the names of the Goddess,
女神的名號
the names that we recite.
我們背誦的名號
We should read them again and again and understand them,
我們要一次又一次的唸誦它們，並要理解它們
the Sanskrit meaning of it.
它們梵文的意義
And it should come to us very easily,
對我們應該是很容易的
because that is how we are going to work out our chakras.
因為這就是我們怎樣成就我們的輪穴
I don't think we have names of Christ,
我不認為我們有基督的名號
it's all right,
這一次
and this time I hope we will try to
我希望唸誦
read some names of Christ.
基督的一些名號
But we have the names of Ganesha but not of Christ,
我們有格涅沙的名號，不是基督
so we'll say the hundred-and-eight names of Shri Ganesh,
所以我們唸誦錫呂‧格涅沙的108名號
and somebody can wash My feet, all right ....
一些人可以清洗我的蓮足，好吧…
Have you?
你有沒有？
Well really, that's the best.
真的，這是最好的
But so, I would say somebody should say now, let's see.
但那麽，我可以說有人現在應該說，讓我們看看
How many names we have? ....
有多少個名號？…
Let Me create the names, and we'll give it to others.
讓我來創造名號，我們會把它給別人
Why should only Gavin keep the names?
為甚麽只有加文保留名號？
It's not like a prime minister of this country,
不像這個國家的首相
you have chosen the leader.
你已經揀選了領袖
Prime minister is paid money for,
首相只是付錢雇用的
she's - that's her job she is doing.
她是…這是她的工作
He is not doing his job.
他不是做他的工作
You all are doing the job of God.
你們全都在做神的工作
So why should there be any such thing that ...
那麽，為甚麽會有這種事情…
Now somebody should read it,
現在有人應該唸誦它
and somebody can.
有人應該唸誦它
Now who will read it?
誰會唸誦它？
Now somebody should read it and somebody can wash My feet.
現在一些人唸誦它，一些人清洗我的雙腳
But don't do it too much, eh?
不要做得太多
This is Christ - it's not easy to absorb.
這是基督，不容易吸收
All right, let's see.
好吧，讓我們看看
Let's see how much love you have for Him,
讓我們看看你有多愛祂
how much you absorb Him ...
你可以吸收祂多少…
Get up now.
現在起來吧
So you must get up to help, some of you.
你必須起來幫忙，你們一些人
And others also.
其他人也一樣
There's nothing to fear that there is ego or anything.
不用害怕有自我或其他
Don't keep back thinking,
不要只是在回想
"Oh, they think I'm just being ... " -  no, run!
啊！他們認為我只是…」不，趕快吧
Run for the job.
趕快工作吧
Now, what is it?
現在，這是甚麽？
Get some things what you need.
拿一些我們需要的東西
Now, who will conduct the puja?
現在，誰帶領崇拜
Bala, you can do it?
巴拉，你可以嗎？
All right, come forward.
好吧，上前來
Some ladies can come also, what's the harm?
一些女士也上前吧，有甚麽關係？
Now come here. ...
現在來這裏吧…
The water and all that ...
水和所有這些…
Now, you being friends,
現在，把你的朋友帶來
you need not trouble too much ...
不用太麻煩了…
Who was born to teach us of His Father Sadashiva,
祂降世教導他父親永恆並至高的神
the everlasting Almighty God. Amen.
濕婆神的旨意。阿門
Aum twameva sakshat Shri Jesus sakshat
Aum twameva sakshat Shri Jesus sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo Namah.
He is the primordial Being, the Aum.
祂是太初之存有，祂是唵
He is Vishnu and the son of Vishnu.
祂是毗濕奴，祂是毗濕奴之子
He is Mahavishnu.
祂是摩訶毗濕奴
He is pure pranava energy.
祂是純粹的生命能量
He contains millions of universes.
祂包容千百萬計的宇宙
He was born in the primordial cosmic egg.
祂由太初宇宙之蛋所生
He was conceived in the heart of Shri Mataji.
祂在錫呂‧瑪塔吉女士心中
He was foretold by the prophets.
祂是先知所預言過的
He was heralded by a star in the east.
祂受東方天上的一顆星歡呼
He was attended by the three Magi,
祂受三位博士探訪，
who were Brahma, Shiva and Vishnu.
祂們是梵天婆羅摩、濕婆神和毗濕奴
He was born in a stable.
祂在馬糟裡出生
He is the teacher.
祂是一位導師
He is a friend of the cows.
祂是牛的朋友
He was attended by cows.
祂受牛的探訪
His father is Shri Krishna.
祂的父親是克里希納
His mother is Shri Radha.
祂的母親是羅陀
He is the Savior who burns all our sins with His fire.
祂是救世主，祂用火燒掉我們的罪惡
He adorns the Agnya Chakra.
祂住於額輪
He is light.
祂是光
He is of the nature of sky.
祂是天空的本質
He is fire.
祂是火
He performed miracles out of His compassion.
祂由於愛心行出神蹟
He whose cloak was touched.
祂的袍為人摸
He is a friend of ascetics.
祂是苦行者的朋友
He is worshipped by families.
祂受家庭的崇拜
Because tapasa - He stands at tapassvi.
因為苦行 ---  祂處於苦行中
Now you see, that's why.
現在你明白，這就是原因
Ascetic, why? Because He is a tapassvi.
苦行者，為甚麽？因為祂是苦行者
His bija mantra is "Ham, Ksham."
祂的根源口訣是Ham(我)和Ksham(寬恕)
He is the forgiver.
祂是寬恕者
He allows us to forgive.
祂讓我們去寬恕
He is the Spirit.
祂是靈
He is born of the Spirit.
祂由靈所生
He who was crucified and resurrected in pure Spirit.
祂是純潔的靈，被釘死十字架上，並從死裡復活
He who rose again after three days.
祂在三天後復活
He is peace.
祂是平安
He absorbs all thoughts.
祂吸收一切的思想
He abides in the Adi Agnya Chakra.
祂住於原初的額輪
He abides in everything,
祂忍受一切
but in human beings in the Agnya Chakra.
在人類的額輪
He is the Aumkara.
祂是 Aumkara.
He abides in everything,
祂忍受一切
but in the human beings He abides in the Agnya Chakra.
在人類中，祂在額輪中忍受
He who promised the Comforter who is Shri Mataji,
祂答應給我們一個保惠師，祂便是錫呂‧瑪塔吉女士
the Holy Spirit.
聖靈的體現
He who returns as a king.
祂以國王的身分回歸
He is Shri Kalki.
祂是迦拉奇
He is the principle of evolution.
祂是進化的原理
He is the support of our evolution.
祂是進化的支持
He is the end of evolution.
祂是進化的終結
He is the support of the universe - Mooladhara.
祂是宇宙的支撐---根輪
He is the evolution from collective subconscious
祂是從集體潛意識進化到
to collective consciousness.
集體意識的過程
He is the narrow gate.
祂是窄門
He is the way to the Kingdom of Heaven.
祂是到天國的道路
He is the narrow gate to the Kingdom of Heaven,
祂是窄門,到天國的道路
and He is the way.
祂是道路
All right.
好吧
He is the silence.
祂是靜默
He is Lord Kartikeya.
祂是我主卡提凱亞
He is Shri Maha Ganesha.
祂是摩訶格涅沙
He is the purity of innocence.
祂是純潔的純真
He is continence.
祂是自制
He is generosity.
祂是慷慨
He is the light in the eyes of Shri Mahalakshmi.
祂是神聖的摩訶拉希什米眼中的光
He is obedient to His Mother.
祂服從祂的母親
He is the perfect Sahaja yogi.
祂是完美的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
He is the perfect brother.
祂是完美兄弟
He is the embodiment of joy.
祂體現了喜樂
He is the embodiment of gentleness.
祂體現了溫和
He spits out the half-hearted.
祂屏棄那些只有一半誠意的人
He condemns the adulterous eyes.
祂譴責淫邪的眼睛
He condemns all fanatics.
祂唾棄那些宗教狂熱主義者
Actually, neutralizes the adulterous eyes.
實際上，中和了淫邪的眼睛
He makes the adulterous eyes innocent,
祂令淫邪的眼睛變得純潔
because He is innocence.
因為祂是純潔
He is uninterested in riches.
祂對財富毫不關心
He gives all riches to His devotees.
祂賜予信眾所有的財富
He is pure white.
祂是純白的
No, this is, you can't say He is uninterested
不，你不能說祂不感興趣
in rituals - what makes you  think?
儀式中，令你想及甚麽？
The rituals which are real ...
儀式是真的…
See, the one who is riches,
你要明白，那些富有的人
how can He be interested in riches?
祂怎會對錢財感興趣？
That's the point ...
這就是重點...
Riches He is.
祂對財富
Not interested at all, because He being the riches
完全不感興趣，因為祂就是財富
- that is gunatita, as you call it - you see,
這是gunatita，你這樣稱呼它
the being and the non-being.
存在體與非存在體
When you are the non-being,
當你不是存在體
you cannot be interested in the being.
你不會對存在體感興趣
Beyond, He is beyond.
超越，祂是超越
He is the  sacred heart.
祂有神聖的心
He wears a crown of thorns.
祂戴上荊棘造的冠冕
He condemns misery.
祂唾棄可憐
He suffered so that we should enjoy.
祂為我們受苦，讓我們快樂
He is a child, yet He is the ever ancient.
祂是個孩童,祂是恆古以來就存在的
He is the Alpha and the Omega.
祂是亞爾發，祂是奧米迦
He gives the kingdom of heaven
祂對最先和最後的人
equally to those who are first or last.
同樣賦與上帝的國
He is ever with us.
祂與我們永遠同在
He is beyond the universe.
祂超越宇宙的
He is the sign of the cross.
祂的象徵是十字架
He is above discrimination.
祂超越辨別能力的
He is the witness.
祂是靜觀者
He is the one who is witnessed.
祂是被見證者
He overcomes temptation.
祂戰勝試探
He exorcises evil.
祂驅除邪惡
He condemns occult practices.
祂唾棄邪術
He is the embodiment of tapas - penance.
祂是苦行（修行）的體現
He worships His father.
祂崇拜祂的父親
He is hallowed by His Father.
祂受祂父親的推崇
He whose name is holy.
祂的名號便是神聖
He is intelligence.
祂是聰明
He is wisdom.
祂是智慧
He is perfect humility.
祂是完全的謙卑
He is angry with materialists.
祂對物質主義者生氣
He destroys ego and absorbs superego.
祂毀滅自我,祂吸入超我
He is the destroyer of desires.
祂是欲望的毀滅者
He is the pure power of desire.
祂是欲望的純潔力量
His church is the heart.
祂的心便是聖殿
He has the eleven destroying powers.
祂具有十一種毀滅力量
He is the destroyer of false prophets.
祂是假先知的毀滅者
He is the destroyer of untruth.
祂是假道理的毀滅者
He is the destroyer of intolerance.
祂是不寬容的毀滅者
He is the destroyer of racialism.
祂是種族主義的毀滅者
He is the destroyer of anger.
祂是憤怒的毀滅者
Of fanaticism - it's very much so.
狅熱，是非常…
He is the herald of the Golden Age.
祂是黃金時代的宣佈者
He is worshipped by our Mother.
祂受母親欣賞
He is praised by our Mother.
祂受母親讚美
He is loved by our Mother.
祂受祂母親鍾愛
He is the one who is chosen.
祂是被揀選出來的
He is awakened in all Sahaja yogis.
祂在所有霎哈嘉士之中都被喚醒
He who rides the white horse at the end of the age.
祂是在末世騎著白馬而來者
He is the end of our fears.
祂是我們恐懼的終結
He guards the gate of our Mother.
祂守護著母親的門戶
He is the only way to the Kingdom of God.
祂是到上帝的國的唯一道路
Aum Shri Mahalakshmi, Mahavishnu sakshat
Aum Shri Mahalakshmi, Mahavishnu sakshat
Shri Mahavirata sakshat
Shri Mahavirata sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo Namah.
I think the word "worshipped" should be "adored by our Mother"
我視「敬拜」這字句應是「受母親敬拜」
because He didn't like it, I think,
我想是因為祂不喜歡
it's catching on the Agnya.
額輪受感染
So it's "is adored by."
所以是「受敬拜」
See, He's so particular - you see,
你看祂是那麽特別
the protocol is not all right, that's why.
禮儀不妥當，這是原因
See - better!
看，好一點！
Agnya was fine. See?
額輪還好，明白嗎？
Some catches there are.
有一點感染
I was wondering which one of them was.
我正奇怪是那一個
Now we'll say, "He is adored by our Mother."
現在我們說︰祂受我們母親所敬拜
He is adored by our Mother.
祂受母親敬拜
Again, three times.
再次，三次
Again.
再一次
He is adored by our Mother.
祂受母親敬拜
See? He's very particular.
明白嗎？祂是非常特別
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們
You got the meaning of that?
明白它的意義嗎？
The description of Mahalakshmi, what She gives you,
描述摩訶拉希什米，她給你甚麽
and also the description about Her relationship with Vishnu,
以及描述她與毗濕奴的關係
with Hari - is Shri Krishna,
以Hari，是錫呂‧克里希納
that She is the beloved of Shri Krishna (Hari)
她是錫呂‧克里希納(Hari)的至愛
Is the beloved of Shri Krishna;
是錫呂‧克里希納的至愛
and that's how it explains how Mahalakshmi,
這就是它怎樣解釋摩訶拉希什米
if She is Mary, then Mary is Radha.
若她是聖母瑪利亞，聖母瑪利亞就是羅陀
This has to be done by boys
這是要由男孩做的
who haven't got the feeling of marriage,
還未有結婚的感覺
or think of it. It has to be that pure.
又或未想結婚的男孩，就是要這樣純潔